Finding Aid for the Adventure Tomorrow Television Scripts PASC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
Adventure Tomorrow television scripts
1958-1964
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC.0235
2.0 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Adventure Tomorrow was a local Los Angeles television series which aired on KCOP, during ca. 1950s-1960s. The collection consists of 240-plus scripts for the program.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9946589263606533
Biography
There is very little information available about Adventure Tomorrow. The program was a local television series which aired in Los Angeles, on KCOP, ca. 1950s-60s.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 240-plus scripts for the Los Angeles based television series Adventure Tomorrow.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by episode title.
Television production and direction -- Archives.; Television scripts.
- Able Means Ability, 4/4/1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Action At Edwards, 9/21/1959 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Aerial Firepower!, 10/16/1963 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Air Force Academy, 10/30/1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Air Shield For This Fleet, 9/27/1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Aircraft Of France, 2/6/1961 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Antidote For Brushfire Wars, 11/13/1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Anti-Missile Missiles, 4/18/1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Anti-Submarine Warfare, 9/25/1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Anti-Submarine Warfare, 10/29/1963 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Apollo Makers (The), 5/7/1962 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Apollo To The Moon, 9/18/1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Assembling The Moon Rocket, 10/14/1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Astrochimps And Rocket Sleds, 10/18/1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Atlas On Target, 9/14/1959 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Atoms At Work, 10/30/1963 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Atoms In Space, 5/28/1962 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Auto Accidents On Purpose, 5/16/1963 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Aviation Roundup, 3/11/1964 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Ballet Of Flight, 1/1/1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Bats, Butterflies And Blood, 4/3/1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Battlefield Helicopters, 11/5/1962 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Beating The Heat, 11/4/1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Behind The Pushbutton, 5/11/1959 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Big Shots Of The Year, 1/26/1959 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Blue Angels - camera angles list, 2/15/1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Boeing 707, 5/6/1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Brief History Of Artillery (A), 4/25/1963 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Brief History Of Bang (A), 4/25/1963 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Britain's Bootstrap Jet, 9/26/1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Britain's Jet Schoolhouse, 10/23/1961 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- British Highlights, 4/30/1962 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- British Roundup, 3/20/1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Bush Pilot, 10/22/1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Carrier Classroom, 2/29/1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Checkmate For Bombers, 9/17/1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Chuting Stars, 6/17/1964 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Computer Magic, 12/18/1961 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Computers And The Thinking Man, 5/16/1960 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Cooper's 22 Orbits, 10/2/1963 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Corporal Story (The), 9/26/1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Countdown At Santa Susana, 4/27/1959 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Courier And Transit, 2/20/1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Day At The Glass Works (A), 3/7/1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Design For Destination, 8/17/1959 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Design for Destruction, 10/14/1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Destinations Of Tomorrow, 2/9/1959 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Detroit Assembly Line, 10/7/1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Detroit Assembly Line Part II, 11/18/1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Different Navy Band (A), 11/14/1960 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Dog-Gone Hound Dogs, 9/18/1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Dr. Klein... Blimp Pilot, 9/10/1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Dr. Klein Meets Ogo, 5/29/1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Engines For Titan, 2/2/1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Farnborough World's Greatest Airshow, 1/25/1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Fastest Man On Wheels, 4/9/1962 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- First Step to The Moon (Rockets III), 9/5/1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Flight of The Titan, 6/1/1959 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Fly Like The Birdies, 1/13/1959 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Fly With Bob Hoover, 1/10/1962 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Flying Firemen, 10/24/1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Flying Giants (The), 5/18/1959 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Flying Mapmakers (The), 3/19/1962 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Flying Stovepipe (The), 6/8/1959 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Flying The Jetliner, 3/21/1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Flying Wing, 3/16/1959 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Flying Wing, The, 1/6/1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Footsoldiers Vs. Jet, 6/14/1964 (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Freedom 7, 10/2/1961 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- French Lesson In Jets (A), 11/7/1960 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Friendship 7 -- The Highlights, 6/4/1962 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- From Sunspots To Talking Fish, 5/14/1962 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Frontier Of The Future, 1/19/1959 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Frontier Of The Future, 8/24/1959 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Geiger Tigers (The), 5/30/1963 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Gemini Progress, 4/20/1964 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Get A Skyhook, 11/20/1963 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Glorious Gasbags (The), 3/23/1959 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Ground Support, 1/15/1964 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Handy Helicopters, 9/19/1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Hardworking Drones, 11/15/1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Heart Research, 2/19/1964 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Helicopters Over L.A., 6/11/1962 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Hercules' New Talents, 2/13/1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- High Speed Eye (The), 3/14/1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Highway In The Sky, 3/28/1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- History Of Rockets, 10/26/1959 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- History of Rockets Part I, 8/15/1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- History of Rockets Part II, 8/22/1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Hit 'Em High, Hit 'Em Low, 1/23/1961 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Hit The Silk, 6/13/1960 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Hot Stuff: Handle With Care, 5/15/1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Hovercraft For Hire, 2/28/1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Hovercraft, Britain's Low-Flying Saucer, 3/5/1962 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- How The Navy Learned To Fly, 10/21/1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- How To Build A Jet Pilot, 8/31/1959 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- How To Build A Nosecone, 8/10/1959 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- How To Stretch An Eclipse, 1/1/1964 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Hurricane Hunters, 5/13/1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hurricane Hunters, 9/12/1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Hurricane Sam, 8/1/1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Hustler Strikes (The), 2/8/1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Hydrofoils, 4/27/1964 (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Iconorama, 6/12/1961 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Inside White Sands, 11/25/1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- It's A Snap, 3/6/1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Jet Bombers Go To Sea, 12/16/1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Jet Propelled Office, 2/7/1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Jet-Propelled Seagull (The), 6/29/1959 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Jets Over Europe, 12/5/1960 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- L.A. International, 9/25/1963 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- L.A.'s Space Age Museum, 4/6/1964 (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Legacy Of A Genius, 12/11/1961 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Life Among The Bees, 12/25/1963 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Living With The Atom, 12/9/1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mach 2 Record Collector, 1/22/1964 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Mariner To Venus, 2/21/1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Martians May Be Dangerous, 12/13/1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Meet The Matador, 9/30/1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Meet The Pregnant Guppy, 4/13/1964 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Meet The Thunderchief, 10/16/1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Meet The X-21, 12/4/1963 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Mighty Atlas (The), 11/11/1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Mighty Like A Missile, 7/1/1959 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Mike vs. Bomber, 2/1/1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miracles All Around Us, 12/21/1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Missile Age Army, 11/27/1961 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Missile Deterrence, 4/23/1962 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Missiles On The Move, 2/22/1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mission To Mars, 4/10/1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Missionary's Airlift, 12/25/1961 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Mobots Is Coming (The), 6/6/1963 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Modern Coast Guard, 2/5/1964 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Modern Minuteman, 3/13/1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Moody..Senses, 3/30/1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Moon Madness, 4/2/1962 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Navy And Isaac Newton (The), 1/9/1961 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Navy Blue Missiles, 3/14/1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Navy's Mighty Midget (The), 2/26/1962 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Navy's Steel Band (The), 1/29/1964 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Norad's Aerial Watchdogs, 11/21/1960 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- North Pole By Nautilus, 7/20/1959 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Nots, 8/29/1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Operation Big Slam, 12/12/1960 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Operation Big Slam, 1/16/1961 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Operation Top Gun, 5/23/1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Operational Minuteman (The), 5/9/1963 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Operational Titan (The), 5/21/1962 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Order In Crowded Skies, 1/8/1964 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Our Base For Space, 5/4/1964 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Our Rockets Wear Two Hats, 5/8/1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Pacific Missile Range, 11/6/1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Paris Air Show, 11/13/1963 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Paris Air Show, 1/29/1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Peace Enforcers (The), 12/6/1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Peashooter, Pop Up And Beyond, 12/28/1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Peenemunde, 5/20/1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Peripatetic Paddlewheel (The), 10/5/1959 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Pershing Story (The), 10/11/1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Phantom Of The Fleet, 12/27/1962 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Pilots, Human And OTherwise, 10/12/1959 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Plain and Fancy Flying, 10/28/1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Plane Is Born (A), 5/25/1959 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Polaris At Sea, 12/4/1961 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Project Centaur, 1/24/1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Project Discoverer, 5/9/1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Project Echo, 10/31/1960 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Project Farside, 6/6/1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Project Mercury: The Astronauts And Their Small World, 6/6/1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Project Mercury: The Hardware, 5/30/1960 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Propjets Made Simple, 4/13/1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Railway Into Space, 3/7/1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Rehearsal For Berlin, 3/21/1963 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Rehearsal For Orbit, 1/15/1962 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Remarkable Delta Rocket (The), 5/2/1963 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Report From Switzerland, 1/2/1961 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Research Into Space, 4/17/1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Return From Outer Space, 6/22/1959 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Rocket Makers (The), 10/17/1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Rockets By The Cluster, 4/11/1963 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Sac's Flying Filling Station, 10/29/1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Sage..The Brain In Your Future, 9/28/1959 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Salute To Thor, 10/10/1960 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Satellite For Science, 3/26/1962 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Satellite High, 8/3/1959 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Saturn Flies, 2/19/1962 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Scott Carpenter's Flight, 10/4/1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Seagoing Spaceport, 1/22/1962 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Shortcut To Space (A), 4/4/1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Skydiving, 2/12/1964 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Snares And Snoopers, 2/16/1959 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Solid As A Rocket, 11/9/1959 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Solid Plus Liquid Equals Space, 6/13/1963 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Solids For Space, 1/8/1962 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- South End Of The World, 4/24/1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Space Age Glass, 11/22/1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Space Age: The Year One, 11/23/1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Space Man Or Robot, 1/18/1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Space Medicine, 12/7/1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Space Medicine, 12/18/1963 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Space Pilot's School, 11/6/1963 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Space Probe, 4/20/1959 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Space Race Review, 2/12/1962 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Space: The Fruits Of Our Labors, 5/18/1964 (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Spacemakers, Pumps And Plastic Hearts, 2/14/1963 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Starbuilders (The), 12/20/1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Starfighters Round The World, 3/28/1963 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Steps To The Moon, 6/7/1964 (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Strategic Air Command, 2/27/1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Supersonic Cops And Robbers, 7/13/1959 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Supersonic SAC, 5/22/1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Supersonic Schoolroom, 5/1/1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Supersonic Wedge, 3/2/1959 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Sword And The Shield (The), 11/27/1963 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Symphony In Steel, 1/30/1961 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Syncom, 3/30/1964 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Target Nevada, 5/27/1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Target USA, 7/25/1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Telstar, 11/29/1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Test Pilot, 6/5/1961 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- The ABC's Of Guided Missiles, 3/12/1962 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- This Is Are Defense, 5/2/1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Thor Story (The), 12/14/1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Thrasher's Sister Subs, 6/24/1964 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Thunder From The Skies, 12/30/1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Titan III Progress, 5/11/1964 (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Titan Story (The), 1/11/1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- To Fly On Ions, 4/16/1962 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Triton's Underwater Orbit, 3/22/1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Trouble Detectives (The), 4/25/1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Turbine Car (The), 2/26/1964 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- U.S. Planetoid #1, 6/15/1959 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Untitled, 11/13/1961 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- V.T.O.L., 11/16/1959 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- V-2 Story (The), 11/2/1959 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Vertijet Teaser, 3/9/1959 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Vigilantes Flying, 11/20/1961 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Vulcan's Modern Forge, 11/28/1960 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Wally Schirra's Flight, 1/3/1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Way Out Newsreel, 5/27/1964 (Box 4, Folder 74)
- We Enter The Space Age, 8/8/1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- WeaTher Satellites, 3/16/1964 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Widest Horizon (The), 4/6/1959 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- World Of Super Cold (The), 5/23/1963 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- World's Biggest Rocket, 10/3/1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- World's Fastest Car, 3/4/1964 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- X Marks The Plane, 2/28/1959 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- X-15, 4/11/1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- X-15 Logbook, 2/5/1962 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- X-17 Story (The), 9/7/1959 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Your Newest Jetliner, 10/4/1963 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Your Personal Helicopter -- Maybe, 12/11/1963 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Zeus Revisited, 10/9/1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)